Guide to the Kentucky Infantry, 6th Regiment, Company Records, 1861-1865 MS 294
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Kentucky Infantry, 6th Regiment, Company Records
1861-1865
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Confederate States of America. Army. Kentucky Infantry Regiment, 6th
MS 294
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
The U.S. Civil War Company records of the 6th Regiment Kentucky Infantry consist of General Orders; descriptive rolls of the regiments's commissioned and non-commissioned officers; a register of men discharged and why; a register of death; a register of deserters; and a descriptive roll of the regiment with physical and vital information.
Historical Sketch
The Sixth Kentucky, a Union Army regiment, was organized in late 1861 with volunteers that came principally from Henry, Jefferson, Kenton, Oldham and Shelby counties. Anderson, Campbell, Fayette, Hardin, Madison, Spencer, Trimble and Woodford counties were also represented, with about 60 men from southern Indiana. Four of the Sixth Kentucky's ten companies were composed principally of German-born residents of Louisville. The Sixth Kentucky was a member of Colonel (later Brigadier General) William B. Hazen's brigade. Hazen's brigade served in the Army of the Ohio and its successor, the Army of the Cumberland. The regiment fought at Shiloh, Stones River, Chickamauga, Brown's Ferry, Orchard Knob, Missionary Ridge, and in the four-month-long Atlanta Campaign. The Sixth Kentucky was at Perryville on the day of the battle, but its division was not called into the fray. However, the Sixth was instrumental in pushing Confederate forces out of Kentucky with frequent skirmishes with Braxton Bragg's rear guard.
The survivors of the three years of heavy service were mustered out in late 1864. Over 110 of its men were killed or mortally wounded. Almost 90 died from disease and illnesses caused by their wounds. By the end of the regiment's three years of service, its rolls had been reduced from approximately 900 men to about 300.
Excerpted from a "Brief History of the Sixth Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (Union)" by Joe Reinhart.
Scope and Contents
The U.S. Civil War Company records of the 6th Regiment Kentucky Infantry consist of General Orders; descriptive rolls of the regiments's commissioned and non-commissioned officers; a register of men discharged and why; a register of death (of what if illness; where and how if battle); a register of deserters; and a descriptive roll of the regiment with physical and vital information. There are also Morning Reports which describe which man had what type of duty and in some cases gives detailed reports of troop movement and skirmishes, and Muster Rolls and returns.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
The records were purchased May 1966.
Related Materials
A photocopied list of officers and men of Company B, 6th Regiment, Kentucky Infantry from History of the Orphan Brigade is included in the MS 294 control folder, WRC. A copy of Joe Reinhart's article, "Brief History of the Sixth Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (Union)" is also located in the control folder.
See also: http://www.rootsweb.com/~jadmire/kyhenry/6kyhist.html.
Index Terms
Subjects
Military; American Civil War (United States: 1861-1865); War
Document Types
military records
Places
United States
- Series I: Ledgers, 15691
  - List of commissioned and non-commissioned officers, register of men transferred, register of men discharged, register of deaths, register of deserters, descriptive roll of regiment, 1861-1864; 15694 (Folder 1)
  - General Orders, 1861-1863; 15693 (Folder 2)
  - Remarks for the Month, Morning Reports, 1861-1864; 15692 (Folder 3)
- Series II: Muster Rolls, 15683
  - Company D, 1861-1862; 15690 (Folder 4)
  - Company D, 1862-1863; 15689 (Folder 5)
  - Company D, 1863; 15688 (Folder 6)
  - Company D, 1863-1864; 15687 (Folder 7)
  - Company A and unidentified company, 1861-1864; 15686 (Folder 8)
  - Company D, 1861-1865; 15685 (Folder 9)
  - Company D, 1862; 15684 (Folder 10)
- Series III: Returns, 15680
  - Company D, 1863; 15682 (Folder 11)
  - Company D, 1864; 15681 (Folder 12)